[
    {
        "question": "Drihten (<em>cweþan</em>) #### word to Noe — God spoke words to Noah",
        "correctAnswer": "cwæþ|cwæð",
        "explanation": "Here 'cweþan' is in the third person singular present form '<em>cwæþ</em>' because the subject is 'Drihten'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Ðu (<em>cweþan</em>) ####, ðæt ðu me lufodest — You said that you loved me.",
        "correctAnswer": "cwæde",
        "explanation": "Here 'cweþan' is in the second person singular present form '<em>cwæde</em>' because the subject is 'Ðu'",
        "commonMistakes": [
            {
                "incorrectAnswer": "cwæþe",
                "explanation": "Don't forget, due to Verner's Law the 'þ' in 'cweþan' becomes 'd' when a suffix is added"
            },
            {
                "incorrectAnswer": "cwæðe",
                "explanation": "Don't forget, due to Verner's Law the 'ð' in 'cweðan' becomes 'd' when a suffix is added"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Hie (<em>cweþan</em>) #### to him. Drihten, syle us ðisne hlaf — They spoke to him. Lord, give us this loaf",
        "correctAnswer": "cwædon",
        "explanation": "Here 'cweþan' is in the plural past form '<em>cwædon</em>' because the subject is 'Hie'",
        "commonMistakes": [
            {
                "incorrectAnswer": "cwæþon",
                "explanation": "Don't forget, due to Verner's Law the 'þ' in 'cweþan' becomes 'd' when a suffix is added"
            },
            {
                "incorrectAnswer": "cwæðon",
                "explanation": "Don't forget, due to Verner's Law the 'ð' in 'cweðan' becomes 'd' when a suffix is added"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Hie geornlice smeadon hwæt he (<em>cweþan</em>) #### — They earnestly considered what he said",
        "correctAnswer": "cwæde",
        "explanation": "Here 'cweþan' is in the third person singular past form '<em>cwæde</em>' because the subject is 'Hie'",
        "commonMistakes": [
            {
                "incorrectAnswer": "cwæþe",
                "explanation": "Don't forget, due to Verner's Law the 'þ' in 'cweþan' becomes 'd' when a suffix is added"
            },
            {
                "incorrectAnswer": "cwæðe",
                "explanation": "Don't forget, due to Verner's Law the 'ð' in 'cweðan' becomes 'd' when a suffix is added"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "He neallas beagas (<em>giefan</em>) #### — He gave no rings",
        "correctAnswer": "geaf",
        "explanation": "Here 'giefan' is in the third person singular past form '<em>geaf</em>' because the subject is 'He'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Hwæt (<em>giefan</em>) #### ðu me? — What are you giving me?",
        "correctAnswer": "giefst",
        "explanation": "Here 'giefan' is in the second person singular present form '<em>giefst</em>' because the subject is 'ðu'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Ge him hleoþ (<em>giefan</em>) #### — Ye gave him shelter",
        "correctAnswer": "geafon",
        "explanation": "Here 'giefan' is in the plural past form '<em>geafon</em>' because the subject is 'Ge'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "He ne (<em>sprecan</em>) #### to ðe, ac ic sprece to ðe — He is not speaking to you, but I'm speaking to you",
        "correctAnswer": "spricþ|spricð",
        "explanation": "Here 'sprecan' is in the third person singular present form '<em>spricþ</em>' because the subject is 'He'",
        "commonMistakes": [
            {
                "incorrectAnswer": "sprecþ",
                "explanation": "Don't forget 'sprecan' undergoes i-mutation in the third person present singular to become 'spricþ'"
            },
            {
                "incorrectAnswer": "sprecð",
                "explanation": "Don't forget 'sprecan' undergoes i-mutation in the third person present singular to become 'spricð'"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Ða (<em>sprecan</em>) #### se ofermoda cyning — Then the proud king spoke",
        "correctAnswer": "spræc",
        "explanation": "Here 'sprecan' is in the third person singular past form '<em>spræc</em>' because the subject is 'se cyning'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Ðu (<em>sprecan</em>) #### wisum wordum — You speak wise words",
        "correctAnswer": "spricst",
        "explanation": "Here 'sprecan' is in the second person singular present form '<em>spricst</em>' because the subject is 'Ðu'",
        "commonMistakes": [
            {
                "incorrectAnswer": "sprecst",
                "explanation": "Don't forget 'sprecan' undergoes i-mutation in the third person present singular to become 'spricst'"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Beowulf beotwordum (<em>sprecan</em>) ####  — Beowulf spoke boastful words",
        "correctAnswer": "spræc",
        "explanation": "Here 'sprecan' is in the third person singular past form '<em>spræc</em>' because the subject is 'Beowulf'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Of ðissum beorgum ðe we ær (<em>sprecan</em>) #### — Of these mountains which we spoke of earlier",
        "correctAnswer": "spræcon",
        "explanation": "Here 'sprecan' is in the plural past form '<em>spræcon</em>' because the subject is 'we'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Maria (<em>sittan</em>) #### be Hælendes fotum — Maria sat by the Saviour's feet",
        "correctAnswer": "sæt",
        "explanation": "Here 'sittan' is in the third person singular past form '<em>sæt</em>' because the subject is 'Maria'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "(<em>sittan</em>) #### him æt wine — They sat at wine",
        "correctAnswer": "sæton",
        "explanation": "Here 'sittan' is in the plural past form '<em>sæton</em>' because the subject is 'Hie'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "For ðæm earfoþum ðe him on (<em>sittan</em>) #### — Because of the burdens that sat heavy on them",
        "correctAnswer": "sæton",
        "explanation": "Here 'sittan' is in the plural past form '<em>sæton</em>' because the subject is 'ðæm earfoþum'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "(<em>sittan</em>) ####  he ðæt biscopsetl an wintra — He occupied that bishop's seat for one year",
        "correctAnswer": "sæt",
        "explanation": "Here 'sittan' is in the third person singular past form '<em>sæt</em>' because the subject is 'He'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "He on his hus eode and his swæsendo (<em>þicgan</em>) #### — He went to his house and consumed his meal",
        "correctAnswer": "þeah|ðeah",
        "explanation": "Here 'þicgan' is in the third person singular past form '<em>ðeah</em>' because the subject is 'He'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Hie (<em>þicgan</em>) #### æppel — They consumed the apple",
        "correctAnswer": "þeagan|ðeagan",
        "explanation": "Here 'þicgan' is in the plural past form '<em>þeagan</em>' because the subject is 'Hie'",
        "commonMistakes": [
        ]
    }
]